Guide to the Alf Heller Collection of Exposition Postcards M2160
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Alf Heller collection of exposition postcards
1911-1931
1851-1985
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Heller, Alfred E.
M2160
1.5 Linear Feet (2 boxes)
Collection of historical postcards commemorating various international expositions primarily in Europe, assembled by donor Alf Heller.
Scope and Contents
Collection of exposition postcards primarily from Europe and England, assembled by donor Alf Heller. The majority are blank, unsent postcards. There is also a file of published material about the Crystal Palace in London, including prints, a newer guide book and a book of photographic views.
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research. Note that material must be requested at least 36 hours in advance of intended use.
Biographical / Historical
Alfred E. "Alf" Heller is a graduate of Stanford University and has donated several historical items to Stanford Special Collections. Heller was founder and president of California Tomorrow and was also the publisher of the newspaper Nevada County Nugget between 1959 and 1979 in Grass Valley, California.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Transfer from Rare Books; 2016. Accession MSS 2016-209.
Postcards.; Europe -- Description and travel.; England -- Description and travel; United States -- Description and travel.; Exhibitions; Trade shows; Heller, Alfred E.; Crystal Palace (Sydenham, London, England)
- Festival of Empire & Coronation Exhibition, London, 1911 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Exposition Universelle de Gand, Leipzig, 1913 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Middelburg Ausstellung, Holland, 1913 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Anglo-American Exposition, London, 1914 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Exposition Internationale, Lyon, 1914 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Schweizerische Landesausstellung, Bern, 1914 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Exposition Coloniale, Marseille, 1922 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Canadian National Exposition, Toronto, 1922 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- British Empire Exhibition, Wembley, England, 1924 (Box 1, Folder 9-10)
- Miscellaneous exposition postcards, 1926 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Sesqui-Centennial International Exposition, Philadelphia, PA, 1926 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Exposicion Internacional de Barcelona, 1929 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Exposition Internationale Anvers (Antwerp, Belgium), 1930 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Stockholmsutstallningen, Sweden, 1930 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Exposition Coloniale Internationale, Paris, 1931 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  Scope and Contents
  Also includes original photographs.
- Esposizione di Torino, Italy, 1911 (Box 1, Folder 17-18)
- Ausstellung Zur Jahrhundert-Feier Der Freiheitskriege, Breslau, 1913 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Jubileumsutstallningen i Goteborg, 1923 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- British Empire Exhibition, Wembley, 1924 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Sesqui-Centennial International Exposition, Philadelphia, PA, 1926 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- 200th Anniversary of Concord, New Hampshire, July 4, 1927 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Exposicion Internacionale, Barcelona, 1929 (Box 2, Folder 4-5)
- Exposition Internationale, Liege, 1930 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Exposicion Ibero-Americana, Seville, Spain, 1930 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Material related to the Crystal Palace in London (Box 2, Folder 8)
  Postcards, guidebook, newspaper article, lithographic prints, published book of photographs, etc.